Guide to the Allan Moll broadcast radio audio collection 1945-1966
Multimedia Archives, J. Willard Marriott Library, University of Utah
- 1965 World Series playback with Sandy Koufax, Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 35)
  Allan Moll reports from the victorious Dodgers Clubhouse where he interviews Sandy Koufax, Dodgers pitcher, Warren Giles, the former Cincinnati representative who moved on to become the President of the National League, and Frank Howard, Dodgers Batter. Sandy Koufax discusses the changes in his pitching from game to game, his view of the Yankees, and his opinions of Frank Howard as a professional batter. In Warren Giles' interview, he discusses his views on the World Series game. In Frank Howards interview, he discusses his batting history, how he felt about the pitches that he received in the World Series game, and his views on Sandy Koufax as a pitcher.
- Winston Churchill's obituary, 1965 January; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 36)
  This tribute, narrated by Allan Moll, is opened with the history of Winston Churchills greatest accomplishments and greatest hardships accompanied by excerpts from the speeches that Churchill gave before and during World War II.
- Special assignment: anti-poverty, 1965 May 30; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 37)
  In this Special Assignment, Allan Moll sits in at City Hall where concerned are discussed regarding a sudden commotion that arose over the local Administration of Anti-Poverty Program and the Youth Opportunities Board. Aired in this program are excerpts from Don Smith who was the core chairman, Augustus Hawkins who was a congressman, Attorney Joseph L. Wyatt, councilmen Tom Bradley and John Haulan, Reverend Brookens and Mayor Sam Yorty. In these excerpts, issues such as the origin of discontent with the Anti-Poverty Program and efforts to resolve the dilemma are discussed. After the sit in, Andy West interviewed Mayor Sam Yorty who discusses his position on the issue at hand and upcoming funds for the Anti-Poverty Program.
- Car smog tests in california, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 38)
  In this program, Allan Moll interviews an unnamed man from the Office of Motor Vehicle Pollution Control Board for the state of California. This motor vehicle pollution expert explains which car parts emit smog and what is being done to reduce the amount emitted. He explains how smog reducing car parts work, their cost, State law requirements for installation of these parts, the adverse effects that they have and the benefits that they offer. He then reviews the statistics for the amount of air pollution that comes from cars, explains the components of smog and inversion levels, and discusses the responsibilities of car owners and manufactures in helping to keep the environment clean and healthy.
- Special assignment: literacy in America, Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 39)
  In this Special Assignment, Allan Moll interviews Phillip Beck who is the director of a reading institute. In this interview Mr. Beck gives the statistics on the percent of illiterate people in the California population and explains the role that the school systems plays in those figures. He discusses the differences between private and public education and introduces a few different approaches to teach people of all ages to read.
- This is the place; big car auto racing, 1947 July 24; Phonograph record (Disc 40)
  a) KDYL Special Events presents the unveiling of This Is The Place in Salt Lake City Utah. The event is opened by a prayer followed by a dedication to the park from President George Albert Smith. In closing we hear from Mahonri M. Young who sculpted the monument from granite found in Cottonwood Canyon.
  2) At this event, twenty of the greatest dirt tract drivers inaugurate the speed derby at the State Fair Grounds. Allan Moll reviews the concepts behind racing and explains how the point system works. Then he conducts interviews with Sunny Epson and his wife as well as Ebb Stienbach.
- King Cole Trio; "Slow Boat" and "Skunk", 1947 September 06; Phonograph record (Disc 41)
  a) Allan Moll announces the live broadcasting of the King Cole trio from Salt Lake City to NBC, coast to coast then they air the performance.
  b) Slow Boat and Skunk are two musical pieces that where popular during the 1940sand 50s. The performing artist is unknown.
- National Broadcasting Compnay (NBC) Miles news; world news with Richard Harkness, 1951 May 22; Phonograph record (Disc 42)
  1) In this newscast, Morgan Matty reports on world news such as the condition of the American military forces, Korea, China, Russia, Britain and Iran. In closing, he takes us live to the Dugway Valley blasting.
  2) In this newscast, Richard Harkness reports on world news such as the spread of Chinese communism, the United Nations and their negotiation plans and the Red Scare in the media and in the government.
- Fisher Brewing newscast by Allan Moll; twilight tapestry, 1947 February 21; Phonograph record (Disc 43)
  1) In this newscast Allan Moll reports on President Johnson's request for money to aid the needy people all over the world, on Senator Van Burens request for military strength to stop Russian communism and on an anticipated civil war in India. Mr. Moll then goes into the sports report and finishes with the weather forecast.
  2) This audio disc contains approximately the first thirty seconds of the music from Twilight Tapestry recorded three different times.
- John Barrymore; Miles news, 1950 August 04; Phonograph record (Disc 44)
  1) This audio disc contains John Barrymore's last performance on NBC before his death in readings from various literary works by William Shakespeare.
  2) In this newscast, Allan Moll reports on American relations with Korea, Russia and London and discusses the atomic energy crisis of the fifties. In closing he reports on news from around the world in two minutes.
- John Barrymore part 1; Charles Denny; John Barrymore Part two, 1950 August 10; Phonograph record (Disc 45a-b)
  1) and 3) John Barrymore's last performance on NBC before his death in readings from various literary works by William Shakespeare.
  2) This is a closed circuit audio disc and is not for re-broadcasting. Charles Denny, the station manager, discusses broadcasting programs and scheduling.
- John Barrymore, 1950 August 17; 1950 August 24; Phonograph record (Disc 46a-b)
  These audio discs contain John Barrymore's last performance on NBC before his death in readings from various literary works by William Shakespeare.
- Hometown U.S.A., 1945 September 16; 1945 September 23; Phonograph record (Disc 47a-d)
  1) Hometown U.S.A was a program designed to honor the Continental Air Command. This particular broadcasting begins with Allan Moll conducting an interview with a Lieutenant from the Air Force followed by a reading of the message that Dwight D. Eisenhower sent to the soldiers on D-Day before the attack. This is followed by an excerpt from a Cornel who survived D-Day. In this excerpt he discusses his personal experiences and emotions on and after D-Day.
  2) Each week Hometown U.S.A honors a different American Air Force Combat Veterans and their hometown. In this broadcasting they honor the veterans Kentucky by listing their names and the names of various companies that assisted in wartime production.
  3) This audio disc pays homage to Cincinnati with a narrated history of Fort Douglas, Fort Thomas and the wartime production that Cincinnati took part in.
  d) In this broadcasting of Hometown U.S.A, Allan Moll interviews a pilot who experienced the Berlin Raid first hand. He then turns the time over to the special guest, linguist Jerry Bergin. In closing Allan Moll reads a letter from.
- undated, Phonograph record (Disc St. Peter)
- Twilight tapestry; air checks, undated; Phonograph record, audiocassette (Disc 48)
  Side b of this audio disc was dubbed onto an audiocassette due to bad condition.
  1) and 2) This Twilight Tapestry is composed of a few musical numbers and a story about spring.
  3) This audio disc contains air checks and various advertisements.
- Pet Milk music show; Town House melodies, 1949 June 18-19; Phonograph record (Disc 49)
  1) The Pet Milk music show was a musical show that was sponsored by Pet Milk.
  2) In this broadcasting of Town House Melodies, vocalists Karen Kemple and Bob Hannon perform various musical numbers composed by Noah Collar.
- Wyoming train wreck; the prophet, 1946 November 14; Phonograph record (Disc 50)
  1) Allan Moll reports live from Wyoming by way of short wave radio when two train engines collide.
  2) This audio disc contains a narrated story of the life of Jesus Christ.
- Richard Harkness; Firestone opera, 1947 July 14; Phonograph record (Disc 51)
  1) In this newscast, Richard Harkness reports on the Governors' conference. He covers such issues as rehabilitating war stricken Europe, taxes, the lack of housing in America and savings bond programs.
  2) This audio disc contains the opera Orpheus and is sponsored by Firestone tires.
- Allan Moll March issue; Zions Cooperative Mercantile Institution (ZCMI) fashion show, 1946 March 17; Phonograph record (Disc 52)
  1) This audio disc contains Allan Moll reading various poems and stories.
  2) On this audio disc, Allan Moll narrates one of the first fashion shows held at the ZCMI shopping center.
- Valentine show (2004 addendum), 1957 May 29; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 53)
- Unidentified audiotape (2004 addendum), undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 54)